Rome, Italy luciancrainic.github.io

LUCIAN DORIN CRAINIC

(+39) 3270499569 crainic.lucian@gmail.com github.com/luciancrainic

ABOUT ME

Hello, I'm a Computer Science student at La Sapienza in Rome. My interests in Computer Science include different fields such as Data Science, Artificial Intelligence and Human Computer Interaction.

I am a hardworking, responsible, trustworthy and ambitious student that really enjoys Computer Science. I am always ready to share my experience and learn from others.

EDUCATION

La Sapienza University

Rome, Italy

Sep 2020 – May 2023 (Expected)

- B.S. in Computer Science
- **Graduate Coursework:** Python, Discrete Math, Java, Computer Architecture, Algorithms, Algebra, Operating Systems, Databases, Computer Networks, Software Engineering, Web and Software Engineering.

IIS Einstein-Bachelet Rome, Italy Sep 2015 – Jun 2020

• IT and Telecomunication High School diploma.

EXPERIENCE

Small Business - AlbaSocial

Rome, Italy

2018 - 2020

- Driven and ambitious Founder of a social media agency dedicated to continous business improvement focused on enhancing revenue and stremlining business operations.
- Built a responsive website that allows a client to buy social media services for different platforms.
- Utilized the API of a service provider, and built an interactive, real-time shop to purchase different services.

Management - KBM Consultants

London, UK

21 March - 25 March 2019

- Professional Resume writing and mentoring skills.
- Impact and uses of social media, creating leads and marketing it.
- Developing the data, product cycle.

Graphic Designer - Freelance

Rome, Italy

2016-2017

- Developed and implemented designs to existing and new product packaging. Developed Business collateral including sell sheets, catalogs, brochures, posters, advertisements, and web assets. Prepared and sent final artwork to vendos to produce.
- Used HTML/CSS, JavaScript in creation and maintenance of personal portfolio website.
- Started with Adobe Photoshop and then learned Adobe Illustrator.

LANGUAGES AND TECHNOLOGIES

- Advanced: Python, GO, Java, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Git, Unix, Vue.js, OpenAPI, MySQL
- Familiar: C, Modelica, SQLite

PROJECTS

WASAPhoto - Academic

- Defined APIs using the OpenAPI standard.
- Designed and developd the server side ("backend") in GO.
- Designed and developed the client side ("frontend") in JavaScript.
- Created a Docker container image for deployment.

WikipediaWebScraper - Academic

- Developed a Wikipedia web scraper in Java with Selenium.
- Designed and Developed a graphic interface in Java Swing.

Portfolio website - Personal

- Developed the frontend with HTML,CSS and Javascript.
- Sharing of photography pictures that i shoot and book reviews.